# **MERT YAZİCİ**

Izmir · 531 790 36 06 · yazici.mert.35@gmail.com www.mertyazici.dev · GitHub · Linkedin

## **SUMMARY**

My professional journey began as an insurance agent, and during my university years, I spent my summers selling souvenirs in tourist areas. After completing my education, I developed an interest in software and became acquainted with SEO, gaining 2 years of experience in this field. Currently, I am utilizing the knowledge I have acquired by creating websites on a freelance basis.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Seo Consultant, Kriko Bilişim

2021 - 2023

- Provided consultancy services to major brands, focusing on e-commerce websites and achieving significant performance improvements for both B2B and B2C businesses.
- Executed comprehensive SEO strategies encompassing technical SEO and various other aspects of search engine optimization.
- Utilized industry-leading tools such as SEMrush, Searchmetrics, and Ahrefs to drive datadriven SEO campaigns.
- Developed and implemented on-page and off-page SEO strategies to enhance website visibility and organic traffic.
- Monitored and reported on SEO performance metrics, providing actionable insights for continuous improvement.

## Sales Associate & Store Manager, Mamouth Shopping

2017 - 2020

• Managed customer relations and product procurement for the store.

## Insurance Technical Specialist & Sales Consultant, Ediz Kurt Sigorta

2010 - 2014

• Issued and marketed insurance policies.

#### **EDUCATION**

Department of Banking and Insurance

2010 - 2013

Anadolu University

**Department of Economics** 

2014 - 2019 (Incomplete)

Dokuz Eylül University

Department of Management Information Systems

2021 - 2023 (Incomplete)

Demokrasi University

Department of Web Design and Coding

2023 - Present

İstanbul University

## ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Technical Skills: CSS3, HTML5, JS, React, Vue, Next, WordPress, Screaming Frog, Searchmetrics, Semrush, Ahrefs, GSC, GA
- Languages: English (intermediate)
- Certifications:
- 1. Udemy Sıfırdan Projelerle Front-End ve React 18.x Öğren Hakan Yalçınkaya
- 2. Laba Eğitim ve Danışmanlık FrontEnd Developer Kursu
- 3. Happy Academy 80 Saat A'dan Z'ye Dijital Pazarlama Eğitimi
- 4. Udemy Web Development HTML, CSS, Node, JavaScript, React, Angular, ASP. NET Core

# **MERT YAZİCİ**

Karşıyaka İzmir • 531 790 36 06 • yazici.mert.35@gmail.com www.mertyazici.dev • GitHub • Linkedin

## ÖN YAZI

Sigorta personeli olarak başlayan iş hayatımda üniversite dönemimde yazları turistik bölgelerde hediyelik eşya satarak devam ettim. Eğitim hayatımı sonlandırdıktan sonra yazılıma olan ilgim nedeniyle SEO ile tanışıp 2 yıl bu alanda deneyim kazandım. Şu anda öğrendiğim bilgileri freelance olarak web sitesi yaparak kullanmaktayım.

# İŞ DENEYİMİ

## Seo Consultant, Kriko Bilişim

2021 - 2023

- Büyük markalara danışmanlık hizmetleri sunarak, özellikle e-ticaret web sitelerine odaklanıp B2B ve B2C işletmeleri için önemli performans iyileştirmeleri elde ettim.
- Teknik SEO ve arama motoru optimizasyonunun çeşitli diğer yönlerini kapsayan kapsamlı SEO stratejileri uyguladım.
- SEMrush, Searchmetrics ve Ahrefs gibi sektör lideri araçları kullanarak veri odaklı SEO kampanyalarını yönettim.
- ,Web sitesi görünürlüğünü ve organik trafiği artırmak için sayfa içi ve sayfa dışı SEO stratejileri geliştirdim ve uyguladım.
- SEO performans metriklerini izleyip raporladım ve sürekli iyileştirme için uygulanabilir görüşler sundum.

## Sales Associate & Store Manager, Mamouth Shopping

2017 - 2020

• Mağaza için müşteri ilişkilerini yönettim ve ürün tedarikini sağladım.

## Insurance Technical Specialist & Sales Consultant, Ediz Kurt Sigorta

2010 - 2014

• Sigorta poliçelerini düzenledim ve pazarladım.

## **EĞİTİM**

Bankacılık ve Sigortacılık Anadolu Üniversitesi 2010 - 2013

**Ekonomi** Dokuz Eylül Üniversitesi 2014 - 2019

Yönetim Bilişim Sistemleri Demokrasi Üniversitesi (Tamamlanmadı) 2021 - 2023

Web Tasarım ve Kodlama

(Tamamlanmadı)

istanbul Üniversitesi

2023 - Halen

#### \_\_\_\_\_

## ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Teknik Yatkınlıklar: CSS3, HTML5, JS, React, Vue, Next, WordPress, Screaming Frog, Searchmetrics, Semrush, Ahrefs, GSC, GA
- Yabancı Dil: English (intermediate)
- Sertifikalar:
- 1. Udemy Sıfırdan Projelerle Front-End ve React 18.x Öğren Hakan Yalçınkaya
- 2. Laba Eğitim ve Danışmanlık FrontEnd Developer Kursu
- 3. Happy Academy 80 Saat A'dan Z'ye Dijital Pazarlama Eğitimi
- 4. Udemy Web Development HTML, CSS, Node, JavaScript, React, Angular, ASP. NET Core